

Soma Utsumi

Software Engineer, Site Reliability Engineer

Tokyo, Japan

SUMMARY

I'm a founding member of Industry Technology Inc, where I serve as CTO. Here I'm driving the development of the SaaS product and providing technical leadership.

I have also served as a SRE on the side, helping to solve business and technical problems from multiple perspectives.

SKILLS

SRE

- SLI/SLO Design
- Postmortem
- · Capacity Planning
- Security
- Observability
- Kubernetes
- Datadog

Platform Engineering

- Architectural Design
- Monitoring
- Cost Management
- CI/CD
- Developer Experience
- Terraform

Cloud

- GCP
- AWS

Backend

- Go
- gRPC
- Connect
- GraphQLMusCol
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL

AREA OF INTERESTS

- Studying English
- SRE
- Workout

WORK EXPERIENCE

2023-11 - Side, SRE in SRE desk

Present enechain Corporation

Duties

Security

Platform Engineering

• Site Reliability

2023-08 - Side, MLOps Engineer in LLM STUDIO

Present Algomatic Inc.

Duties

• Building learning infrastructures for LLM

• Building inference servers for LLM

• Building application infrastructures for products

2019-04 - **Co-founder,CTO**

Present Industry Technology Inc.

Duties

• Development of enterprise SaaS for building management companies

• Architecture Design

Spec Refinement

Tech Strategy

Recruiting

2018-04 - Data Analyst, Digital Marketer

2019-06 Gunosy Inc.

Duties

• Planning A/B tests

Analyzing the user data

2018-01 - Intern, Backend Engineer

2018-03 ZUU Co.,Ltd.

Duties

• Development of the internal system

EDUCATION

2014 - 2018 Bachelor of Engineering

The University of Tokyo

Design of a preoperative evaluation system for elderly patients using a generalized linear model

DETAILED RESUME

https://github.com/soma00333/resume/blob/main/README.md